okay so we have been asked when will
this instruction comment we already know
that this one will broadcast the result
in cycle 16 that means it cannot commit
in the next cycle so basically in cycle
15 we have committed this in cycle 16 we
cannot commit this because the broadcast
is happening in 16 we can only commit it
at 17 next cycle 18 we will check if
this can commit yes it can because it
has already broadcasted its result and
it's done and then finally this becomes
19 so the correct answer here is 19 you
can see that to determine this we didn't
actually have to figure out what really
happens here but let's do that for the
sake of exercise so in cycle 17 this
gets marked down 32 gets deposited in
register one we check the mapping for
our one is a drop for no we leave the
rat alone and free this robin three in
cycle 18 we can commit this we put minus
one in our four we check the entry for
our four is it pointing to rob five it
is we change the right to point to this
are four and we freed the Rob entry and
finally in cycle 19 we commit this
instruction we put the value of r3 into
r1 we then check the Rob entry for r1 is
it pointing to rob 6 yes it is make it
point to here and we can free this Rob
entry and this concludes really what
happens in this whole program as far as
you know cycles 1 through 19 our concern